timebucks.com 2019-03-21

# Privacy Policy

This web site is owned and managed by Australian Clearing Pty Ltd.

To reach us via e-mail, you can email support@TimeBucks.com

This privacy policy sets out how TimeBucks.com uses and protects any information that you TimeBucks.com when you use this website.

TimeBucks.com is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

By using TimeBucks.com, you signify your agreement to our privacy policy as stated above. Note that this policy may be revised periodically without notice. Please re-read this policy prior to submitting any personal information if you have concerns about how your information is being collected and used. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from Sunday 7th July 2013.

**_Who We Are_**  
**TIMEBUCKS** _(‘we’ or ‘us’ or ‘our’)_ gather and process your personal information in accordance with this privacy notice and in compliance with the relevant data protection Regulation and laws. This notice provides you with the necessary information regarding your rights and our obligations, and explains how, why and when we process your personal data.

**_Information That We Collect_**  
**TIMEBUCKS** processes your personal information to meet our legal, statutory and contractual obligations and to provide you with our products and services. We will never collect any unnecessary personal data from you and do not process your information in any way, other than as specified in this notice. 

**_The personal data that we collect from is: -_**

  * Name
  * Date of Birth
  * Home Address
  * Personal Email
  * Business Email
  * Home Telephone Number
  * Mobile Telephone Number
  * National Insurance Number
  * Passport Number
  * Driver’s License Number
  * Special Category Data ( _i.e. health/medical information, details about religion, sexuality etc)_

**_We collect information in the below ways: -_**  
_(i.e. online form, website orders, survey questions, application ip, downloads or any task on our website that requires you to submit data._

Our web-server also records IP addresses from all visitors to our site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our site, to analyze trends, to track user movement, and to gather broad demographic information all for the purpose of continually improving our website and delivering personalized, custom content. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information, and their collection is standard procedure in most web-server environments.

**_How We Use Your Personal Data_**  
**TIMEBUCKS** takes your privacy very seriously and will never disclose, share or sell your data without your consent; unless required to do so by law. We only retain your data for as long as is necessary and for the purpose(s) specified in this notice. Where you have consented to us providing you with promotional offers and marketing, you are free to withdraw this consent at any time.  **_The purposes and reasons for processing your personal data are detailed below: -_**

  * _We collect your personal data in the performance of a contract or to provide a service and to ensure that orders are completed and can be sent out to your preferred address_
  * _We collect and store your personal data as part of our legal obligation for business accounting and tax purposes_
  * _We have a legal obligation to share your personal data with our survey and data providers whom to you are conducting market research towards._
  * _We will occasionally send you marketing information where we have assessed that it is beneficial to you as a customer and in our interests. Such information will be non-intrusive and is processed on the grounds of legitimate interests_

**What we do with the information we gather**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:  
Internal record keeping.  
We may use the information to improve our products and services.  
We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.  
From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.  
We may collect information to improve our Web site’s content and to notify consumers about our site’s updates. Security 

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**_Your Rights_**  
You have the right to access any personal information that **TIMEBUCKS** processes about you and to request information about: -

  * What personal data we hold about you
  * The purposes of the processing
  * The categories of personal data concerned
  * The recipients to whom the personal data has/will be disclosed
  * How long we intend to store your personal data for
  * If we did not collect the data directly from you, information about the source

If you believe that we hold any incomplete or inaccurate data about you, you have the right to ask us to correct and/or complete the information and we will strive to do so as quickly as possible; unless there is a valid reason for not doing so, at which point you will be notified. 

You also have the right to request erasure of your personal data or to restrict processing ( _where applicable)_ in accordance with the data protection laws; as well as to object to any direct marketing from us. Where applicable, you have the right to data portability of your information and the right to be informed about any automated decision-making we may use.   
If we receive a request from you to exercise any of the above rights, we may ask you to verify your identity before acting on the request; this is to ensure that your data is protected and kept secure.

**_Sharing and Disclosing Your Personal Information_**  
We do not share or disclose any of your personal information without your consent, other than for the purposes specified in this notice or where there is a legal requirement. **TIMEBUCKS** uses **a THIRD PARTY CLEARING HOUSE** to provide the below services and business functions; however, all processors acting on our behalf only process your data in accordance with instructions from us and comply fully with this privacy notice, the data protection laws and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

**Australian Clearing**  
Providing a clearing facility for payments of Timebucks users. They agree to our privacy policy which is compliant with GDPR. They have access to your email accounts for payment processing and sometimes may need to verify your identity, as does Timebucks.

**_Safeguarding Measures_**  
**TIMEBUCKS** takes your privacy seriously and takes every reasonable measure and precaution to protect and secure your personal data. We work hard to protect you and your information from unauthorised _access, alteration, disclosure or destruction and have several layers of security measures in place, including but not limited to - SSL, TLS, encryptions, pseudonymisation, restricted access, IT authentication, firewalls, anti-virus/malware. ****_

**_Transfers Outside the EU_**

**TIMEBUCKS** utilise some **** products or services ( _or parts of them_ ) that may be hosted/stored in non-EU countries, which means that we may transfer any information which is submitted by you through the website outside the European Economic Area ("EEA") for the below purposes: - i.e. website hosting, email servers, marketing database, survey marketing, application installs or any other service available on the Timebucks website. ****

Therefore, when you **TIMEBUCKS,** the personal information you submit may be stored on servers which are hosted in non-EU countries. Where this is the case, we will take steps to ensure that those providers use the necessary level of protection for your information and abide by strict agreements and measures set out by the globally required standard as per GDPR **** to protect your data and comply with the relevant data protection laws.

**_Consequences of Not Providing Your Data_**  
You are not obligated to provide your personal information to TIMEBUCKS, however, as this information is required for us to provide you with our services/deliver your products/legitimate interests, we will not be able to offer some/all our services without it. 

**_Legitimate Interests_**  
As noted in the _‘How We Use Your Personal Data’_ section of this notice, we occasionally process your personal information under the legitimate interests’ legal basis. Where this is the case, we have carried out a thorough Legitimate Interests’ Assessment (LIA) to ensure that we have weighed your interests and any risk posed to you against our own interests; ensuring that they are proportionate and appropriate. 

We use the legitimate interests’ legal basis for processing your data for the completing of surveys or other paid marketing arrangements that you, the user are opting in for through our website, for processing is based on legitimate interests] and have identified that our interests are aligned with yours as you are using our service. 

**_How Long We Keep Your Data_**  
**TIMEBUCKS** only ever retains personal information for as long as is necessary and we have strict review and retention policies in place to meet these obligations. We are required under UK tax law to keep your basic personal data _(name, address, contact details_ ) for a minimum of 6 years after which time it will be destroyed.

Where you have consented to us using your details for direct marketing, we will keep such data until you notify us otherwise and/or withdraw your consent.

**_Special Categories Data_**  
Owing to the products, services or treatments that we offer, **TIMEBUCKS** sometimes needs to process sensitive personal information ( _known as special category data_ ) about you, to verify and validate certain activity that has occurred with our providers and through our website. Where we collect such information, we will only request and process the minimum necessary for the specified purpose and identify a compliant legal basis for doing so. 

Where we rely on your consent for processing special category data, we will obtain your explicit consent through a signature. You can modify or withdraw consent at any time, which we will act on immediately, unless there is a legitimate or legal reason for not doing so. 

**_Marketing_**  
**_CONSENT EXAMPLE_** ** __**

Occasionally, TIMEBUCKS **** would like to contact you with the information that we provide. If you consent to us using your contact details for this purpose, you have the right to modify or withdraw your consent at any time by using the opt-out/unsubscribe options or by contacting **TIMEBUCKS** directly.

If you **_consent_** to us contacting you with the above-mentioned marketing and offers, we will only contact you via email 

**_Lodging A Complaint_**  
**TIMEBUCKS** only processes your personal information in compliance with this privacy notice and in accordance with the relevant data protection laws. If, however you wish to raise a complaint regarding the processing of your personal data or are unsatisfied with how we have handled your information, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority. 

**_Cookie Notice_** _ ___

A **_‘cookie’_** is a small piece of data sent from a website and stored on the user’s computer by the user’s web browser while the user is browsing. When you visit a site that uses cookies for the first time, a cookie is downloaded onto your computer/mobile device so that the next time you visit that site, your device will remember useful information such as items added in the shopping cart, visited pages or logging in options.

Cookies are widely used in order to make websites work, or to work more efficiently, and our site relies on cookies to optimise user experience and for features and services to function properly. 

Most web browsers allow some control to restrict or block cookies through the browser settings, however if you disable cookies you may find this affects your ability to use certain parts of our website or services. For more information about cookies visit [https://www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/). 

**Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**Controlling your personal information**

Personal information collected may be transferred and shared in the event of a sale of TimeBucks.com

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

\- Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes where such a box is available   
\- If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at support@TimeBucks.com  
\- Members can edit their personal information by clicking on My Profile / Options located in the upper right corner of each page.  
\- Registrants can un-register by writing to support@TimeBucks.com. Once you have established a member account with us, you can opt-out of future promotional mailings by clicking on My Profile/ Options and changing your settings.  
\- We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.  
\- You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to support@TimeBucks.com.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at support@TimeBucks.com.

At TimeBucks.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by TimeBucks.com and how it is used.

**Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, TimeBucks.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
TimeBucks.com does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**  
.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on TimeBucks.com.  
.:: Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to TimeBucks.com and other sites on the Internet.  
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site.   
These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on TimeBucks.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

TimeBucks.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. TimeBucks.com privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

_“This website uses Pollfish web plugin. Pollfish is an on-line survey platform, through which, anyone may conduct surveys. Pollfish collaborates with Developers of applications for smartphones and website owners in order to have access to users of such applications/websites and address survey questionnaires to them. This website uses and enables Pollfish cookies. When a user connects to this website, Pollfish detects whether the user is eligible for a survey. Data collected by Pollfish will be associated with your answers to the questionnaires whenever Pollfish sents such questionnaires to eligible users. For a full list of data received by Pollfish through this website, please read carefully Pollfish respondent terms located at https://www.pollfish.com/terms/respondent. By using this website you accept this privacy policy document and you hereby give your explicit consent for the placement of a Pollfish cookie in your system and the processing by Pollfish of the aforementioned data. Furthermore, you are informed that you may disable Pollfish operation at any time by using the Pollfish “opt out section” available on Pollfish website or by disabling “third party cookies” from your browser’s settings. We once more invite you to check the Pollfish respondent’s terms of use, if you wish to have more detailed view of the way Pollfish works works._

_APPLE, GOOGLE AND AMAZON ARE NOT A SPONSOR NOR ARE INVOLVED IN ANY WAY IN THIS CONTEST/DRAW. NO APPLE PRODUCTS ARE BEING USED AS PRIZES.”_
